Guide to Records Concerning Real Property and Legal Transactions near Cripple Creek, Colorado
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Records concerning real property and legal transactions near Cripple Creek, Colorado
1861-1972
1890-1910
WA MSS S-2641
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
57.4
(201 boxes) + 17 rolls, 5 broadside folders
Manuscript and printed indexes and summary volumes prepared by regional abstract companies to record the history of real property titles and other financial and legal transactions in Fremont, Teller, and El Paso counties in Colorado, 1861-1972, with the bulk of the collection dating from the height of the Cripple Creek gold rush, 1890-1910. The records consist chiefly of summary accounts created by regional abstract companies from official records maintained in the Fremont, Teller, and El Paso county clerks' offices to document the acquisition and transfer of real property, mining claims, powers of attorney, and tax delinquencies. The records created by abstract companies are accompanied by small groups of business records from local institutions and individuals, as well as 22 printed maps and one disbound volume of plat maps from the region.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Brian Levine on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 1997.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
History of the Cripple Creek Region, Colorado
The Cripple Creek Region encompasses land surrounding the communities of Cripple Creek and Victor in Colorado, southwest of Colorado Springs near the base of Pikes Peak. On October 20, 1890, Robert Miller Womack (1844-1909) discovered a deposit of rich gold ore, which he called the El Paso Lode. Within three years, the population of the region increased from five hundred to over ten thousand. The increasing population, as well as political differences between area miners and mine owners, resulted in the division of El Paso County and a portion of Fremont County to create Teller County in March 1899. The population of the region declined steadily during the early twentieth century as the mines became exhausted and the cost of mining rose relative to the price of gold. Mining increased briefly in 1934 when the federal government raised the price of gold, but all gold mines ceased operation during World War II. Some mines reopened after the war, but all mines in the district were closed by 1961.
Scope and Contents
Manuscript and printed indexes and summary volumes prepared by regional abstract companies to record the history of real property titles and other financial and legal transactions in Fremont, Teller, and El Paso counties in Colorado, 1861-1972, with the bulk of the collection dating from the height of the Cripple Creek gold rush, 1890-1910. The records consist chiefly of summary accounts created by regional abstract companies from official records maintained in the Fremont, Teller, and El Paso county clerks' offices to document the acquisition and transfer of real property, mining claims, powers of attorney, and tax delinquencies. The records created by abstract companies are accompanied by small groups of business records from local institutions and individuals, as well as 22 printed maps and one disbound volume of plat maps from the region.
The records for many of the abstract companies include indices, abstracts arranged by date and type, and records related to sales of real estate for delinquent taxes. Abstract companies represented in the collection include Colorado Springs Abstract Company; Cripple Creek Abstract Company; Cripple Creek District Abstract Company; Cripple Creek, Teller County, Abstract Company; El Paso and Fremont Abstract Company; El Paso County Abstract Company; El Paso County Abstract and Title Guaranty Company; Security Abstract & Title Company; Smith, Barton, McDonald & Co.; Teller and El Paso Abstract Company; and Teller County Abstract Company.
The collection includes a single volume created by the City Treasurer of Cripple Creek Colorado from April 7, 1897 to April 19, 1899, a small group of material created by local businesses, a small amount of financial records for the United Mine Workers of America in 1933, and groups of material created by attorney Hildreth Frost and mining engineer Arthur J. Ventress.
Businesses and organizations whose histories are documented include the Colorado Trading and Transfer Company; Cripple Creek State Bank; First National Bank of Cripple Creek; Golden Cycle Land Corporation; Gould Consolidated Mining Company; Lind Auto Service; Mary McKinney Mining Company; Mechanics' and Traders' Insurance Company of New Orleans; Stratton-Independence Ltd.; and Western Union Telegraph Company.
Maps in the collection chiefly document mining operations in the region. Locations include Allman, Arequa,Cameron, Cripple Creek, Gillett, Goldfield, Independence, Lawrence, and Victor. Several maps also document discrete gold mines; one map depicts the grounds of the Myron Stratton Home in Colorado Springs, Colorado.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Records of Identified Abstract Companies 1871-circa 1940. II. Records of Unidentified Abstract Companies, 1861-1940. III. Records of Businesses and Organizations, circa 1895-circa 1972. IV. Records of Individuals, 1901-1926. V. Maps, 1892-1935.
Mining districts -- Colorado; Gold mines and mining -- Colorado -- Cripple Creek; Gold mines and mining -- Colorado -- Cripple Creek Region; Mineral industries -- Colorado -- Cripple Creek; Mineral industries -- Colorado -- Cripple Creek Region; Mines and mineral resources -- Colorado -- Cripple Creek; Mines and mineral resources -- Colorado -- Cripple Creek Region; Mines and mineral resources -- Colorado -- Cripple Creek -- Maps; Mines and mineral resources -- Colorado -- Cripple Creek Region -- Maps; Real property -- Colorado -- Cripple Creek; Real property -- Colorado -- Cripple Creek Region; Cripple Creek (Colo.); Cripple Creek Region (Colo.); Maps (documents) -- Colorado -- Cripple Creek
- Records of Identified Abstract Companies, 1871-circa 1940; Series I; 21.7; (72 boxes)
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically into ten subseries for each abstract company.
  Companies representated in this series consist of Colorado Springs Abstract Company; Cripple Creek Abstract Company; Cripple Creek District Abstract Company; Cripple Creek, Teller County, Abstract Company; El Paso and Fremont Abstract Company; El Paso County Abstract Company; El Paso County Abstract and Title Guaranty Company; Security Abstract & Title Company; Smith, Barton, McDonald & Co.; Teller and El Paso Abstract Company; Teller County Abstract Company.
  - Colorado Springs Abstract Company, 1871-1935
    Biographical/Historical note
    Colorado Springs Abstract Co. was an abstract company based in Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1890-circa 1909.
    This subseries is arranged under four headings: Indices, Abstracts of Legal Instruments in El Paso and Teller Counties by Date, Abstracts of Legal Instruments in El Paso County by Type, Sale Records for Delinquent Tax in Teller County
    - Indices, circa 1878-1905
      Arranged chronologically.
      - Index to Judgments, El Paso County, circa 1878-circa 1939 (Box 1 Oversize)
        Scope and Contents
        Alphabetical index of judgments that includes the debtor, creditor, case number, amounts, and notes.
      - Index to Tax Sale Records, Lands and Mines, 1881-1905 (Box 2 Oversize)
        Index to mines in Ranges 60-71, arranged by range, township, and section. Includes an alphabetical list of mining claims.
      - Index to Tax Sale Records, Lots, 1891-1904; (1 volume) (Box 3 Oversize)
        Index to lots sold in towns, additions, and subdivisions in El Paso County and Pueblo County, including Colorado City, Colorado Springs, Manitou Springs.
        Laid-in list indexes the locations in the volume.
    - Abstracts of Legal Instruments in El Paso County by Type, 1871-1896
      Arranged alphabetically, then sequentially by volume title.
      Abstracts of legal instruments, probably in El Paso County.
      Alphanumeric designations for volumes refer to designations applied to the original record book in the county clerk's office, not to a sequence of volumes in the abstract company's office. Consequently a bound volume may abstract several volumes of legal instruments.
      - Volume A, 1871-1887 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        Abstracts of plats of subdivision.
      - Volume C and Volume D, 1888-1889 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Volume 45, Volume 201, Volume 219, Volume 228, 1881 February 10-1896 January 14 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        Volume 45 is split into two sections in the volume. The first section abstracts patents from February 10 to August 9, 1881. The second section abstracts patents from November 4, 1890, to January 14, 1896.
        Volume 201 abstracts trusts and mortgages from November 8, 1894 to December 6, 1895.
        Volume 219 abstracts trusts and mortgages from December 11, 1895, to January 14, 1896.
        Volume 228 abstracts a variety of legal instruments from December 16, 1895, to January 14, 1896.
      - Volume 46, Volume 177, and Volume183, 1881 April 15-1895 January 8 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        Abstracts of powers of attorney and trustee deeds.
        Volume 46 dates from April 15, 1881, to June 25, 1892.
        Volume 177 dates from June 28, 1894, to January 8, 1895.
        Volume 183 dates from August 10 to October 15, 1894.
      - Volume 116 (Warranties), 1890 July 31-1891 July 11 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Volume 117 (Quit Claim Deeds), 1890 October 8-1892 October 25 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Volume 118 (Trust Deeds), 1890 February 13-September 29 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Volume 128 (Warranties), 1891 July 13-1892 February 24 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Volume 141 (Dismissals, Judgments, Levies, Liens, Lis Pendens, and Releases), 1892 July 19-1894 December 4 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Volume 144 (Warranties in the Hayden Placer Company subdivision near Fremont, Colorado), 1892 February 16-1896 February 27 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Volume 147 (Warranties), 1892 July 30-1893 April 12 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Volume 148 (Warranties), 1893 April 12-December 20 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Volume 150 (Variety of Legal Instruments), 1892 July 6-1893 July 11 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Volume 152 (Quit Claim Deeds), 1892 October 25-1894 May 21 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Volume 155 (Trusts), 1893 March 3-1896 January 13 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Volume 157 (Trustee Deeds), 1893 March 29-1896 January 11 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Volume 158 (Warranties), 1893 February 23-1894 June 4 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Volume 159 (Trusts), 1894 July 3-1896 January 17 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Volume 161 (Releases), 1893 February 17-1894 January 2 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Volume 162 (Assignments, Trusts, and Mortgages), 1893 April 8-1894 October 26 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Volume 164 (Variety of Legal Instruments), 1893 July 10-1894 January 11 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Volume 166 (Warranties), 1893 December 20-1894 June 8 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Volume 167 (Variety of Legal Instruments), 1894 January 11-June 5 (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - Volume 168 (Releases), 1894 January 3-December 12 (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - Volume 170 (Trusts), 1894 March 9-1896 January 9 (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - Volume 174 (Variety of Legal Instruments), 1894 June 7-December 29 (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - Volume 175 (Quit Claim Deeds), 1894 January 26-1895 October 26 (Box 11, Folder 27)
      - Volume 176 (Dismissals, Judgments, Levies, Liens, Lis Pendens, and Releases), 1894 December 4-1896 January 14 (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - Volume 177 (Powers of Attorney), 1894 June 28-1895 January 7 (Box 11, Folder 29)
      - Volume 178 (Bonds and Leases), 1894 April 16-1896 January 15 (Box 11, Folder 30)
      - Volume 179 (Warranties), 1894 June 4-1895 August 2 (Box 12, Folder 31)
      - Volume 180 (Trusts), 1894 April 18-1896 January 21 (Box 12, Folder 32)
      - Volume 181 (Trusts), 1894 April 18-1896 January 14 (Box 12, Folder 33)
      - Volume 183 (Releases), 1894 July 20-1896 January 10 (Box 12, Folder 34)
      - Volume 187 (Warranties), 1895 November 15-1896 January 14 (Box 13, Folder 35)
      - Volume 190 (Warranties), 1894 June 11-1895 January 8 (Box 13, Folder 36)
      - Volume 191 (Warranties), 1895 January 9-September 14 (Box 13, Folder 37)
      - Volume 192 (Warranty Deeds), 1895 September 14-December 28 (Box 13, Folder 38)
      - Volume 193 (Warranties), 1895 December 28-1896 January (Box 14, Folder 39)
      - Volume 201 and Volume 219, 1894 November 8-1896 January 14 (Box 14, Folder 40)
        Volume 201 abstracts a variety of legal instruments fromNovember 8, 1894 to December 10, 1895.
      - Volume 203 (Attachments and Levies), 1894 December 12-1896 February 3 (Box 14, Folder 41)
      - Volume 204 (Variety of Legal Instruments), 1894 December 31-1895 June 3 (Box 14, Folder 42)
      - Volume 205 (Releases), 1894 December 12-1895 August 20 (Box 15, Folder 43)
      - Volume 205 and Volume 216, 1894 November 7-1896 January11 (Box 15, Folder 44)
        Volume 205 abstracts releases from December 14, 1894, to November 1, 1895.
        Volume 216 abstracts relases from November 7, 1894, to January 11, 1896
      - Volume 206 (Warranties), 1894 September 24-1896 January 13 (Box 15, Folder 45)
      - Volume 212 (Public Trusts), 1895 February 7-1896 January 2 (Box 15, Folder 46)
      - Volume 213 (Warranties), 1895 October 17-1896 January 7 (Box 16, Folder 47)
      - Volume 214 (Variety of Legal Instruments), 1895 June 3-October 16 (Box 16, Folder 48)
      - Volume 216 (Releases), 1895 November 6-1896 January 14 (Box 16, Folder 49)
      - Volume 217 (Quit Claim Deeds), 1895 October 26-1896 January 14 (Box 16, Folder 50)
      - Volume 218 (Variety of Legal Instruments), 1895 October 16-1896 January 7 (Box 17, Folder 51)
      - Volume 228 (Variety of Legal Instruments) and Volume 229 (Variety of Legal Instruments), 1895 December 16-1896 January 15 (Box 17, Folder 52)
        Volume 229 abstracts a variety of legal instruments, January 3-15, 1896.
      - Volume 230 (Warranties), 1895 August 5-1896 January 11 (Box 17, Folder 53)
    - Abstracts of Legal Instruments in El Paso and Teller Counties by Date, 1897-circa 1908
      - T-49, Entries 49000-50998, 1897 December 20-1898 January 19 (Box 18, Folder 54)
      - T-57-58, Entries 57000-58999, 1898 June 1-July 27 (Box 18, Folder 55)
      - T-59-60, Entries 59000-60999, 1898 July 27-September 26 (Box 18, Folder 56)
      - T-61-62, Entries 61000-62999, 1898 September 26-November 23 (Box 18, Folder 57)
      - T-63, Entries 63000-63999, 1898 November 25-December 19 (Box 18, Folder 58)
      - T-64, Entries 64000-64999, 1898 December 19-1899 January 9 (Box 18, Folder 59)
      - T-65, Entries 65000-65999, 1899 January 10-February 3 (Box 18, Folder 60)
      - T-66, Entries 66000-66999, 1899 February 4-March 1 (Box 18, Folder 61)
      - T-67-68, Entries 67000-68281, 1899 March 1-April 3 (Box 18, Folder 62)
      - T-0, Entries 1-1000, 1899 April 1-May 10 (Box 19, Folder 63)
      - T-1, Entries 1001-2000, 1899 May 10-June 12 (Box 19, Folder 64)
      - T-2, Entries 2001-2999, 1899 June 12-July 15 (Box 19, Folder 65)
      - T-3, Entries 3000-3999, 1899 July 15-August 14 (Box 19, Folder 66)
      - T-4, Entries 4000-4999, 1899 August 14-September 9 (Box 19, Folder 67)
      - T-5, Entries 5000-5999, 1899 September 9-October 3 (Box 19, Folder 68)
      - T-6, Entries 6000-6999, 1899 October 3-21 (Box 19, Folder 69)
      - T-7, Entries 7000-7999, 1899 October 21-November 13 (Box 20, Folder 70)
      - T-8, Entries 8000-8999, 1899 November 13-December 4 (Box 20, Folder 71)
      - T-9, Entries, 9000-9999, 1899 December 4-26 (Box 20, Folder 72)
      - T-10, Entries 10000-10999, 1899 December 26-1900 January 11 (Box 20, Folder 73)
      - T-11, Entries 11000-11999, 1900 January 11-31 (Box 20, Folder 74)
      - T-12, Entries 11999-12999, 1900 January 31-February 24 (Box 20, Folder 75)
      - T-13, Entries 12999-13999, 1900 February 24-March 21 (Box 20, Folder 76)
      - T-14, Entries 14000-14999, 1900 March 21-April 17 (Box 21, Folder 77)
      - T-15, Entries 15006-15996, 1900 April 17-May 10 (Box 21, Folder 78)
      - T-16, Entries 15997-16997, 1900 May 10-June 5 (Box 21, Folder 79)
      - T-17, Entries 17000-17996, 1900 June 5-30 (Box 21, Folder 80)
      - T-18, Entries 17997-19002, 1900 July 2-31 (Box 21, Folder 81)
      - T-19, Entries 19003-19996, 1900 July 31-August 27 (Box 21, Folder 82)
      - T-20, Entries 19997-21001, 1900 August 27-September 21 (Box 21, Folder 83)
      - T-24, Entries 24000-24999, 1900 December 14-1901 January 3 (Box 22, Folder 84)
      - T-25, Entries 25000-26016, 1901 January 3-26 (Box 22, Folder 85)
      - T-26, Entries 26017-27007, 1901 January 26-February 23 (Box 22, Folder 86)
      - T-28, Entries 28000-29017, 1901 March 23-April 24 (Box 22, Folder 87)
      - T-30, Entries 30003-30999, 1901 May 29-July 3 (Box 22, Folder 88)
      - T-31, Entries 31000-32003, 1901 July 3-August 13 (Box 22, Folder 89)
      - T-32, Entries 32004-33004, 1901 August 13-September 23 (Box 22, Folder 90)
      - T-33, Entries 33005-34001, 1901 September 23-October 31 (Box 22, Folder 91)
      - T-34, Entries 34002-34997, 1901 November 1-December 9 (Box 23, Folder 92)
      - T-36, Entries 36000-37011, 1902 January 11-February 18 (Box 23, Folder 93)
      - T-37, Entries 37012-37999, 1902 February 18-March 27 (Box 23, Folder 94)
      - T-38, Entries 38000-38997, 1902 March 27-May 12 (Box 23, Folder 95)
      - T-39, Entries 38998-39996, 1902 May 12-July 1 (Box 23, Folder 96)
      - T-40, Entries 39997-40999, 1902 July 1-August 28 (Box 23, Folder 97)
      - T-41, Entries 41000-42000, 1902 August 28-October 23 (Box 23, Folder 98)
      - T-42, Entries 42001-43005, 1902 October 23-December 11 (Box 23, Folder 99)
      - T-43, Entries 43006-43999, 1902 December 12-1903 January 27 (Box 23, Folder 100)
      - T-44, Entries 44000-44994, 1903 January 27-April 3 (Box 24, Folder 101)
      - T-45, Entries 44995-46002, 1903 April 4-June 23 (Box 24, Folder 102)
      - T-45, Entries 45006-46002, 1903 April 4-June 23 (Box 24, Folder 103)
      - T-46, Entries 46003-47001, 1903 June 24-September 19 (Box 24, Folder 104-105)
        2 copies.
      - T-47, Entries 47002-47995, 1903 September 21-December 16 (Box 24, Folder 106)
      - T-48, Entries 47996-49004, 1903 December 17-1904 March 2 (Box 24, Folder 107)
      - T-49, Entries 49005-49998, 1904 March 3-May 23 (Box 24, Folder 108)
      - T-50, Entries 49999-51000, 1904 May 23-August 29 (Box 24, Folder 109)
      - T-51, Entries 51001-52007, 1904 August 29-December 7 (Box 25, Folder 110)
      - T-52, Entries 52008-53001, 1904 December 8-1905 February 11 (Box 25, Folder 111)
      - T-53, Entries 53003-54002, 1905 February 14-May 2 (Box 25, Folder 112)
      - T-54, Entries 54003-55008, 1905 May 3-July 20 (Box 25, Folder 113)
      - T-55-56, Entries 55010-56999, 1905 June 21-1906 January 4 (Box 25, Folder 114)
      - T-57-58, Entries 56998-59006, 1906 January 4-June 30 (Box 25, Folder 115)
      - T-59, Entries 59000-60005, 1906 June 30-October 20 (Box 25, Folder 116)
      - T-60, Entries 59999-61002, 1906 October 20-1907 January 30 (Box 25, Folder 117)
      - T-61, Entries 61000-61999, 1907 January 30-May 23 (Box 26, Folder 118)
      - T-62, Entries 62000-62999, 1907 May 23-October 18 (Box 26, Folder 119)
      - T-Pages, circa 1908 (Box 26, Folder 120)
        Index to entries 17956-50047 and the books the instruments appear in.
      - Books and Pages, circa 1908 (Box 26, Folder 121)
        Index to entries 80828-118030 that describe warranty deeds and refers to the books the instruments appear in.
    - Sale Records for Delinquent Tax in Teller County, 1903-1905
      - Book 5 and Book 6, 1903 November 16-1904 November 26 (Box 27 Oversize)
        Book 5 documents the sale of property for delinquent taxes November 16-17, 1903, with certificate entries 2464-5313.
        Book 6 documents the sale of property for delinquent taxes November 25-26, 1904, with certificate entries 5314-8088.
      - Book 7, Entries 1-2370, 1905 November 25-27 (Box 28 Oversize)
  - Cripple Creek Abstract Company, 1887-1894
    This subseries is arranged under two headings: General Index of Lots and Abstracts of Legal Instruments by Type
    Cripple Creek Abstract Company was based in Colorado Springs, Colorado, circa 1887-1907.
    - General Index of Lots, circa 1887-1907. (Box 29 Oversize)
      Index to property lots in towns, additions, and subdivisions. Settlements include Arequa, Cripple Creek, Fremont, Gillett, Goldfield, Lawrence, and Victor.
    - Abstracts of Legal Instruments by Type, 1887-1894
      - Volume A (Mine Location Certificates and Notices), 1887 January 19-1892 May 16 (Box 30, Folder 122)
      - Volume B (Mine Location Certificates), 1891 August 14-1892 January 9 (Box 30, Folder 123)
      - Volume E, 1884 March 20-1892 March 14 (Box 30, Folder 124)
        Chiefly abstracts warranty deeds in the Town of Fremont.
        Page 17 abstracts the platting of the Town of Fremont in El Paso County by Horace W. Bennett and Julius A. Myers on November 4, 1891.
        Pages 1-14 also include entries for patents, quit claim deeds, receipts, release deeds, and trust deeds.
      - Volume F, 1892 March 14-1893 February 15 (Box 31, Folder 125)
        Chiefly abstracts of warranty deeds and quit claim deeds in Fremont, as well as the Hayden Placer Company subdivision northeast of Fremont.
      - Volume G (Mine Deeds), 1891 December 1-1892 June 27 (Box 31, Folder 126)
      - Volume H (Variety of Legal Instruments), 1879 November 28-1894 November 3 (Box 31, Folder 127)
  - Cripple Creek District Abstract Company, 1901
    This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    Cripple Creek District Abstract Company was an abstract company based in Cripple Creek, Colorado, circa 1895-circa 1915.
    - Tax Sale Record, Teller County, Entries 4143-7261, 1901 November 19-20 (Box 32 Oversize)
    - Name Judgments, undated (Box 33 Oversize)
      Index to debtors in judgments.
  - Cripple Creek, Teller County, Abstract Company, 1897-1902
    Cripple Creek, Teller County, Abstract Company was an abstract company active in Cripple Creek, Colorado, from circa 1897-1902.
    - Lot Book, 1897 May 8-1899 April 1 (Box 34 Oversize)
      Volume records entry numbers for property lots in Cripple Creek and other municipalities in El Paso County.
      Arranged by locality and therein by blocks and property lots.
    - Miscellaneous Lot Book, Teller County, circa 1899-1902 (Box 35 Oversize)
      Volume records entry numbers for property lots in municipalities and subdivisions of Teller County.
    - Land Book, No. 1, circa 1900 (Box 36 Oversize)
      Arranged by range, township, and section.
      Index to lands in Ranges 68-71.
  - El Paso and Fremont Abstract Company, 1895-1899
    The subseries is arranged chronologically.
    El Paso and Fremont Abstract Company was an abstract company in Cripple Creek, Colorado, circa 1895-circa 1900.
    - Cripple Creek Lot Book, 1895-1897 (Box 37 Oversize)
      Index to legal instruments applied to real estate in Cripple Creek, Colorado, as well as other municipalities, including Gillett and Pisgah Park.
    - Index to Abstracts, 1898-1899 (Box 38 Oversize)
      Index to lands in Ranges 68-71, which are presented by range, township, and section.
    - Index to Abstracts, circa 1906 (Box 39 Oversize)
      Alphabetical index by grantors to the entry numbers of the abstracts.
  - El Paso County Abstract Company, circa 1895-1900
    El Paso County Abstract Company was an abstract company active in Cripple Creek, Colorado, circa 1886-1905.
    - Index to Mines, Volume C, circa 1895-1900 (Box 40 Oversize)